<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog Isaac Verminck</title>
    <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog Isaac Verminck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 23:15:51 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://isaacverm.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/28-11-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 23:15:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/28-11-2019/</guid>
      <description>What does it all mean?
  Truth.
USSR grooves.
  I was right!
Zoveel te doen.
  No one is forever as happy as they seem in any given moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/26-11-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 21:07:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/26-11-2019/</guid>
      <description>I had a bad dream&amp;hellip;
Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid, bad dreams are only dreams.
What a time you chose to be born.
  Forest bathing
So much to unpack.
Ignatius Timothy Trebitsch-Lincoln, born Abraham Schwarz, AKA Ignaz Thimoteus Trebitzsch, AKA Moses Pinkeles.
Of Jewish descent, he spent parts of his life as a Protestant missionary, Anglican priest, British Member of Parliament for Darlington, German right-wing politician and spy, Nazi collaborator and Buddhist abbot in China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualize average goals per game in Processing</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/visualize-average-goals-per-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 09:36:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/visualize-average-goals-per-game/</guid>
      <description>In a previous analysis I made a graph showing the average number of home and away goals by season. For some time I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with Processing but only ever focused on small examples instead of a real project. Reproducing the original ggplot2 graph mentioned above seems like a good start. Nothing massive, still feasible.
Parts of the graph What exactly did the original plot look like?
We can discern these elements:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/19-11-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 11:53:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/19-11-2019/</guid>
      <description>So many possibilities with Processing.
Groucho Marx.
His father was called &amp;ldquo;Frenchie&amp;rdquo; by his sons throughout his life, because he and his family came from Alsace in France.
Marx and Lennon, Marx and Lenin.
Nice sweater.
  There&amp;rsquo;s a starman waiting in the sky He&amp;rsquo;d like to come and meet us But he thinks he&amp;rsquo;d blow our minds
  Leningrad Experimental Graphics Laboratory.
That break.
  Gastrodiplomacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis scores Belgian soccer league</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/scores.jpl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 13:16:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/scores.jpl/</guid>
      <description>Analysis made on request. Wanted to explorer scores in the Belgian League. Was quite interesting how much interesting things you can do with a modicum of data. I just focused on the raw scores without linking them to teams or anything and already several, more or less interesting, questions came up naturally.
Code here, analysis itself hosted on RPubs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/16-11-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 12:30:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/16-11-2019/</guid>
      <description>An artist invited Germans to come and be symbolically gased with car exhaust fumes in a former synagogue.
&amp;ldquo;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t afraid but I felt a sense of threat. This realisation shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be lost in this day and age.&amp;rdquo;
Treffende vergissing.
The Disaster Artist.
  Sleeping.
And I looked, and behold a pale horse: and his name that sat on him was Death, and Hell followed with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/14-11-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 22:20:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/14-11-2019/</guid>
      <description>First entry I ever noticed on RPubs. Holy duality of pie chart and calling every document final. Hope the author is ok.
“I could come up with something else of my own again, put it out on a label, tour, etc. It’s just gotta feel free if that happens. I will probably honestly be 40 or 50 when that happens and extremely fat.”
I work on R packages that alleviate some of the pain of transforming and presenting data in a dreary office environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possible rank changes next gameweek Jupiler Pro League</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/possible-rank-changes-jpl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 22:05:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/possible-rank-changes-jpl/</guid>
      <description>Made a post about possible rank changes for teams in the Jupiler Pro League. Felt inspired to try to replicate this post on r/dataisbeautiful. Integrating rmarkdown with Hugo didn&amp;rsquo;t seem straightforward so I decided to publish it to RPubs and link to it from here.
Code for this post can be found on GitHub . Used the package structure again as in the reproducible analysis series and found it very enjoyable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible analysis: literate programming</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-literate-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 18:43:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-literate-programming/</guid>
      <description>Issue When starting off as a beginner doing data analysis you often start with hacking together some scripts. You pick whatever you can find, throw it in the mix and let everything run. These scripts create output like plots, tables, &amp;hellip; which you manually copy afterwards into some document. There are several reasons why this is frankly an excruciating way of working:
 if some output changes you have to manually copy the changed results to the document where you write the analysis changing some parameters of your analysis requires rerunning everything the explanation of what your code does is totally decoupled from the code itself  All this doesn&amp;rsquo;t really favor reproducible analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible analysis: documentation</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 14:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-documentation/</guid>
      <description>Issue We wrote the code, we wrote the tests but we didn&amp;rsquo;t specify explicitly how the code can be used. Take for example the calculateAutoCorrelation function. From its name we can infer it should return some kind of auto correlation coefficient. But how exactly is this correlation calculated? What kind of lag we take into account? Those questions can more easily be answered if we add some metadata to the functions we created.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible analysis: testing</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 10:45:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-testing/</guid>
      <description>Issue When writing code we have some expectations about what it should do. We&amp;rsquo;d like it do something and, even better, do exactly what we want. Verifying this is harder than it seems. You can load a function, run it with some data and check manually if you like the results. However, this scales pretty badly as your code base grows. It becomes impossible to manually check all the details and accidents are bound to happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consonant value</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/technical-notes/consonant-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 20:45:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/technical-notes/consonant-value/</guid>
      <description>Problem Calculate the word value of any word. Word value is defined as the sum of the values of the characters of any consecutive consonant string.
Solution Steps:
 split word in substrings of consonants value each letter in a substring sum the values in a substring find substring with highest sum   function solve(s) { splitCons = str = str.split(/a|e|i|o|u/).filter(subStr = subStr != &#34;&#34;) valueLetters = str = str.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count the smiley faces</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/technical-notes/count-the-smiley-faces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 15:17:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/technical-notes/count-the-smiley-faces/</guid>
      <description>Problem Create a function counting how many valid smileys there are in an array.
Solution The solution seems to need these functions:
 a function to split a smiley in its characters some functions to check if eyes, mouth or nose are valid  Then loop over all smileys and split/check each of them.
 function countSmileys(arr) { splitSmiley = smiley = smiley.split(&#34;&#34;) checkEyes = splittedSmiley = { validEyes = [&#39;:&#39;,&#39;;&#39;] eye = splittedSmiley[0] return validEyes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/07-11-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 11:08:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/07-11-2019/</guid>
      <description>Murderball was invented by the Quadfather.
The author’s explanation is that humans were essentially happy and satisfied with their lives. When they became civilized, the concept of progress led to misery.
    They came to do good, they did very well indeed.
To emphasize the work ethic in Protestantism relative to Catholics, he notes a common problem that industrialists face when employing precapitalist laborers: Agricultural entrepreneurs will try to encourage time spent harvesting by offering a higher wage, with the expectation that laborers will see time spent working as more valuable and so engage it longer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/05-11-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 22:08:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/05-11-2019/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1 till chapter 9 of Leviticus is practically a cook book.
2:15 And thou shalt put oil upon it, and lay frankincense thereon: it is a meat offering.
Someone likes his herbs.
3:10 And the two kidneys, and the fat that is upon them, which is by the flanks, and the caul above the liver, with the kidneys, it shall he take away.
Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too greasy.
The absurdity tag is the best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/04-11-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 23:18:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/04-11-2019/</guid>
      <description>What to do if you&amp;rsquo;re bored.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/02-11-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 17:33:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/02-11-2019/</guid>
      <description>Old Believers, you have to update!
After the implementation of these revisions, the Church anathematized and suppressed—with the support of Muscovite state power—the prior liturgical rite itself, as well as those who were reluctant to pass to the revised rite.
That’s forcing people to upgrade, no depreciation warning.
Things have changed.
1993:
  now:
  Twist after twist.
  Laughing is easy, I would if I could.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible analysis: package development</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-package-dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 11:12:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-package-dev/</guid>
      <description>Issue Packages are used to share your R code with others. Why then should this be the first topic tackled? Couldn&amp;rsquo;t we make our code shareable after we made something to actually share? Well, I actually don&amp;rsquo;t make the analysis a package mainly for sharing it (even though it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have). Packages also have the very nice side effect they enforce conventions. Other packages (e.g. testthat) build on these conventions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/01-11-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 19:14:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/01-11-2019/</guid>
      <description>Boycott is a person.
Anna Karenina principle.
All happy families are alike; each unhappy family is unhappy in its own way.
John Donne.
He spent much of the money he inherited during and after his education on womanising, literature, pastimes, and travel. In 1601, Donne secretly married Anne More, with whom he had twelve children. In 1615 he was ordained deacon and then Anglican priest, although he did not want to take Holy Orders and only did so because the king ordered it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible analysis: example</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 15:20:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-example/</guid>
      <description>Stating the obvious here, but before we can start playing around with the code we need code to play around with. As said in last post each step in the data analysis cycle will have its own function as an example.
Concerns about how to structure this code are not relevant at the moment. First things first so we throw all the functions together in a file called analysis.R. This file is also used to &amp;ldquo;orchestrate&amp;rdquo; (between quotation marks since orchestration in this case is just running each function after another).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible analysis: outline</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 11:31:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/reproducible-analysis-outline/</guid>
      <description>Motivation Last analysis post I made I hit quite a few stumbling blocks making the analysis take longer than expected. When reflecting on why this was the case I realized I hadn&amp;rsquo;t taken reproducibility into account. I made the post in the span of a week and already I realized parts were not documented well enough, not tested well enough, code versions weren&amp;rsquo;t tracked as they should, &amp;hellip; All this can be put under the banner of reproducibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/30-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 22:05:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/30-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>‘Automating’ comes from the roots ‘auto-‘ meaning ‘self-‘, and ‘mating’, meaning ‘screwing’.
Test automation must be the absolute superlative then.
Skin in the game: if because of a bug in devtools a member of R-core gets angry with you, I will send you a handwritten apology note. Just forward me the email and your address, and I&amp;rsquo;ll get a card in the mail.
Sounds a bit too much like an American inspiring life quote but still true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/29-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 23:10:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/29-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>  Miss Sexy Impeachment???
It&amp;rsquo;s spelled Russian and Belarusian with just 1 S!. Never noticed before and no idea why there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between Russian and Belarusian if both have their origin in Россия.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/28-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 23:08:55 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/28-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Lover&amp;rsquo;s grave
I can read.
It is magnificent, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? You see, the thing about shock &amp;hellip; is not that it upsets some people, I think; I think that it gives others a momentary joy of liberation, as we realized in that instant that the social rules that constrict our lives so terribly are not actually very important.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/27-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 19:41:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/27-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>The following method is sometimes used.
    Personal life.
That&amp;rsquo;s the question.
West Coast synthesis is generally linked to the early synth designs of Don Buchla and Serge Tcherepnin, two California-based - hence the name - synth pioneers.
Serge Tcherepnin, born in France, Chinese mother, Russian father but somehow his style of music is called West Coast :).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/26-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 19:38:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/26-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Some interesting eavesdropping.
The moment those drums kick in&amp;hellip;
Just under a century ago, the Soviet Union embarked on one of the strangest attempts to reshape the common calendar that has ever been undertaken. As Joseph Stalin raced to turn an agricultural backwater into an industrialized nation, his government downsized the week from seven to five days. Saturday and Sunday were abolished.
In place of the weekend, a new system of respite was introduced in 1929.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPs commission attendances</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/mps-commission-attendances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 14:14:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/mps-commission-attendances/</guid>
      <description>Scope of this post Article which inspired this post I was triggered to write this post because of an interesting article in De Tijd from some years ago which I recently stumbled upon again. Maarten Lambrechts investigated which members of the Flemish parliament are industrious and which are&amp;hellip; less so.
Focus on commission attendances To make this more concrete he looked at the number of initiatives and questions by parliamentarians in the Flemish Parliament.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/25-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 12:18:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/25-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Almost poetry
  Failed company wanted to charge $15 for $10 in quarters.
Clean as a whistle.
  But neither the &amp;ldquo;Spurs&amp;rdquo; nor Ajax are Jewish clubs, and their number of Jewish fans is not particularly high. So why the Jewish symbolism?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/24-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 22:33:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/24-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>All of the sudden I felt like someone punched me in the stomach with a baseball bat. I got the wind knocked out of me and stumbled backwards. When I looked up there was a 40 oz. bottle at my feet. It had hit me in the gut/dick.
The perpetrator was a 300 lb. black sister who was standing right below me at my monitor. I looked her right in the eye and she waved me forward, as if she was going to tell me a secret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/23-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 23:04:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/23-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Идти.
At any given moment, all sorts of objects are drifting in the ocean, a surprising number of them Americans. The Coast Guard plucks 10 people a day out of the ocean, on average.
Portrait of an Inessential Government Worker.
Need to do more research on this.
Postman to Paris.
We stopped talking about football. That was a problem, because football was our life.
On the pitch, strange things started to happen for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/22-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 21:27:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/22-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Sankey diagram
Pushing wood.
Mesmerizing Oskar Fischinger.
  How much longer can this nonsense go on?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/21-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 21:39:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/21-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>This decision was made to increase the amount of funding received from the European Union, which dedicates a third of its budget (50 billion euros) to less economically developed regions for investments in infrastructure, such as schools and hospitals. Yet when regions improve economically, they no longer qualify for the same amount of funding. As a type of statistical gerrymandering, governors of these regions—like in Hungary—have redrawn their borders in order to keep the money flowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/20-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 20:20:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/20-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Troposphere 5
  Andy Warhol New York Diet.
“When I order in a restaurant, I order everything that I don’t want, so I have a lot to play around with while everyone else eats,” he wrote in The Philosophy of Andy Warhol. “Then, no matter how chic the restaurant is, I insist that the waiter wrap the entire plate up like a to-go order, and after we leave the restaurant I find a little corner outside in the street to leave the plate in, because there are so many people in New York who live in the streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/18-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:18:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/18-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>#YouTubeRegrets is a crowdsourced public awareness campaign run by the nonprofit Mozilla. Mozilla collected YouTube users’ stories about the platform’s recommendation engine leading them down bizarre and sometimes dangerous pathways.
Photoshop before Photoshop.
Sommige dingen veranderen nooit.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/17-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 21:24:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/17-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Österreich and its hiding.
Dutch police are questioning an Austrian man after a family of six were found in a secret room at a remote farmhouse in the Netherlands where they are believed to have been living for nearly a decade.
  Criminal activity of government informants.
Ich???
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cypress commands: selecting elements</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/cypress-selecting-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 09:38:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/cypress-selecting-elements/</guid>
      <description>In this post and the following one I&amp;rsquo;ll go over the most basic Cypress commands which are:
 selecting elements act on these elements  Selections are discussed in this post, I keep the action part for the next post.
Examples are based on the Cypress kitchen sink example site(often slightly modified to make the point more clear in context of this post). This example app covers all existing Cypress commands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/16-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 22:28:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/16-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Nah.
Newly introduced young woman: “There are two things I don’t like about you…your new moustache and…your new political party.”
Churchill: “Pray do not disturb yourself, you are not likely to come into contact with either.”
Tal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/15-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 23:21:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/15-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>How the hell can a person
go to work in the morning
and come home in the evening
and have nothing to say.
  Goe poeier!
но время и случай для всех их.
Экклезиаст, глава 9, стих 11    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a simple CLI with Click to learn Russian (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/cli-russian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 13:53:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/cli-russian/</guid>
      <description>Goal Unix philosophy In line with the Unix philosophy I wanted to build a small system which is as user-friendly as possible (even though I might be the only user). I chose a system which would help me with a personal goal namely learning Russian.
Learning Russian Recently I scraped example phrases for the most common Russian words. Based on Zipf&amp;rsquo;s law it makes sense to really focus on the most common words since the frequency of any word is inversely proportional to its rank in the frequency table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/14-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 23:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/14-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Penitentials were handbooks carried by some priests in the Middle Ages that delineated various sins for private confession and their penances. They were full of strict limitations as to what constituted pious behavior. They went on and on. To digest it all, James A Brundage, a scholar of the Crusades, aggregated the complex rules about sex into this excellent flowchart.
Play it fucking loud.
  My state of mind&amp;rsquo;s all purple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/13-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 12:10:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/13-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>People think that creativity comes from freedom. That&amp;rsquo;s a fundamental misunderstanding. Creativity comes from obstacles, limitations and questions.
Game of life, so easy and so complex.
Wonder if that woof sound has a name.
          Make each program do one thing well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/11-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 14:48:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/11-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Petrus Alexiowitz, tsaar van Moskou, groothertog, heeft zittend aan de rand van deze fontein de wateren verrijkt met de wijn die hij heeft gedronken om drie uur in de namiddag op 16 april 1717.
Доверяй, но проверяй (words are the wise man&amp;rsquo;s counters and the fool&amp;rsquo;s money)
вера = trust
До and про refer to completion, so almost no difference between to check and to trust.
Road trip.
There&amp;rsquo;s value in randomly picking up books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/09-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 23:02:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/09-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Tatiana Samoilova in Летят журавли.
+++++
Audrey Hepburn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/08-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 22:23:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/08-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>The UK is the biggest tax haven.
For decades, places such as Anguilla, the British Virgin Islands, Gibraltar and others sold the companies that people hide behind when committing their crimes. But in recent years, the world has changed – those jurisdictions have been cajoled, bullied and persuaded to keep good records of company ownership, and to reveal those records when police officers come looking. They are no longer as useful as they used to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/07-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 23:22:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/07-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Turing tarpit.
Beware of the Turing tar-pit in which everything is possible but nothing of interest is easy.
Einst kam ich auf eine mögliche Vorstellung die Hölle betreffend. Die Hölle ist eine Ansammlung einzelner Personen, die den Großteil ihrer Zeit damit verbringen, eine Arbeit zu erledigen, die sie nicht mögen und die sie nicht besonders gut beherrschen.
It wasn’t until the next morning that I realized I was a thief.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/06-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 21:35:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/06-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>You are just a goy!
  Ben, j’ai été éduqué par des femmes, hein. C’est pour ça que je suis lesbienne.
Not a bad game at all and at least I played without any major blunders. Hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened for a long time.
 You want to separate the creative process of seeing that the geometry is there for a fork from the editing process of analyzing whether the fork can be made profitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/05-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 13:16:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/05-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Everything we do is interpreted and translated time and again as it works its way down through all of the metaphors and abstractions (In the beginning was the Command Line).
In an art project that has been compared to The Truman Show, Big Brother and the Charlie Kaufman film Synecdoche, New York, a Russian artist has paid 400 people to live for three years in a fictional but functioning Stalin-era research institute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/04-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 17:15:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/04-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>WW2 material still in use today&amp;hellip;
  Nixon.
THE POSITION The position is To withhold Information And to cover up This is Totally true. You could say This is Totally untrue.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most common data manipulations implemented in awk and dplyr</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/most-common-data-manipulations-dplyr-awk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 14:51:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/most-common-data-manipulations-dplyr-awk/</guid>
      <description>Goal of this post We compare the most common data manipulations between dplyr and awk in terms of functionality.
As explained perfectly in the tidyverse article there are 5 types of common data manipulations:
 filter select mutate summarise arrange  I go over each of these manipulations and show using examples in dplyr and awk how to implement them.
Some aspects of these data manipulations are not covered in this article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/03-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 21:42:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/03-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Everyone needs their asylum:
It is an asylum or &amp;ndash; what do they call them now? &amp;ndash; a rest home, for the infirm, the aged, the discontent, and the otherwise incompetent. Look at the three of us &amp;ndash; we are the University. The stranger would not know that we have so much in common, but we know, don&amp;rsquo;t we. We know well.
Telling tales of drunkenness and cruelty.
  золотая осень</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/02-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 21:56:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/02-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Midas.
Robots fighting. So many styles.
    Cleaning up those Youtube pearls one by one.
  Koala.
Because of its small brain, the koala has a limited ability to perform complex, unfamiliar behaviours. For example, when presented with plucked leaves on a flat surface, the animal cannot adapt to the change in its normal feeding routine and will not eat the leaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/01-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 22:01:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/01-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Cut up your hair, straighten your curls. Well, your problems hide in your curls.
Hopper.
Didn&amp;rsquo;t plan to go back to Super Hexagon ever again but CANNOT RESIST.
Thursday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/30-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 23:00:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/30-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Carrier bag theory.
Not only is the carrier bag theory plausible, it also does meaningful ideological work — shifting the way we look at humanity&amp;rsquo;s foundations from a narrative of domination to one of gathering, holding, and sharing. Because I am, despite my best efforts, often soppy and sentimental, I sometimes imagine this like a really comforting group hug. But it’s not, really: the carrier bag holds things, sure, but it’s also messy and sometimes conflicted</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/29-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 23:32:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/29-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Sorry little hedgehog!
Demesne is pronounced as dimain. Mindblowing.
Structured procrastination:
Anyone can do any amount of work, provided it isn&amp;rsquo;t the work he is supposed to be doing at that moment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/28-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 15:11:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/28-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Another chess analysis but this time I annotated a bit different than I did for the one of 24-09-2019:
 less focus on strategy only using local analysis tags  Blunders made are still quite big. These have to be purged first before making sound strategic decisions pay off.
By default Lichess annotates your game with automated comments like blunder, mistake,&amp;hellip; I found those quite annoying but since there&amp;rsquo;s no option to turn them off somehow forcing you to manually remove them one by one, for the time being I choose to only use local analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/26-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 21:50:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/26-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Yeah.
Being in New York compounded a feeling I had been experiencing, of profound dissociation from my own life. I knew, as I wandered through museums with friends and video-chatted with Ian, that I needed to leave the tech industry. I was no longer high on the energy of being around people who so easily satisfied their desires––on the feeling that everything was just within reach. The industry’s hubris and naïveté were beginning to grate; I had moral, political, and personal misgivings about Silicon Valley’s accelerating colonization of art, work, everyday life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/25-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 21:33:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/25-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Nice intro to my programming course book. Fuck all that serious shit!
Christian the absolute mad lad.
From the book by C.V. Wedgwood I&amp;rsquo;m reading on the Thirty Years&amp;rsquo; War.
How to make sure you get your money if you pass a village:
He had issued startling letters, suggestively burnt at the four corners, and bearing the words &amp;lsquo;Fire! Fire! Blood! Blood!&amp;rsquo; to every sizeable village he passed.
Or how to handle a right arm amputation graciously:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/24-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 22:49:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/24-09-2019/</guid>
      <description> Quite a bad game on my part with some horrendous blunders at the end as the cherry on the cake. But at least I made a post game analysis for once.
Some general things to remember are:
 dare choose the more aggressive move if possible (why not go for that sweet queen exchange???) do not play when it gets too late (but I know that rule will always be broken)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/23-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 22:15:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/23-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Hehe.
Article about a creepy subject that isn&amp;rsquo;t so creepy.
With lots of informative pictures:
Could be.
A disappearance begins internally, experienced en masse, but with each one—roses, photographs, and fruit follow—long-coated, stone-faced Memory Police sweep through the village, ensuring that all traces of the disappeared concept or object is gone for good. What exactly causes disappearances is never addressed; instead, the mystery lies in how far they&amp;rsquo;ll go, and what role the Memory Police play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/22-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 19:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/22-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Rehearsing Russian course 1 of 16/09/2019 (p.273-277).
глагол: verb
sing/song: петь/песня
eat/food: есть/еда
drink/drink: пить/напиток
wash/soap: мыть/мыло
+++++
петь (по)
пить (пь)
мыть (мо)
+++++
я ем
ты ешь
он ест
мы едим
вы едите
они едят
+++++
he ate: он ел
we washed: они мыли
weak/strong: слабый/громкий
hot/cold: горячий/холодный
low/high: низкий/высокий
usually: обычно
table wine: столовое вино
singer: певец/певица
drunk: пьяный
often: часто
foreigner: иностранец (иной + страна = other + country)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/19-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 22:32:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/19-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Nothing much today but maybe this mystery finally gets resolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/18-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 21:49:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/18-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>The 11-23 most common verbs in Russian.
Some verbs are skipped because they form perfective/imperfective pairs. For example there&amp;rsquo;s делать/сделать but at the moment I only focus on remembering the easiest form (whether perfective or imperfective).
Main version:
   Russian English remark verb     На этой станции поезд стоит 10 минут. The train stops for ten minutes in this station. стан - ции стоять   Я думаю о тебе.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/17-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 21:45:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/17-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>The 10 most common verbs in Russian with some handy phrase to remember them by.
Added multiple phrases for some verbs (e.g. стать) who have multiple, widely divergent meanings.
   Russian English remark verb     Так было, так есть и так будет всегда. So it was, so it is, and so it will always be! National anthem of Russia быть   Легко сказать! Easy to say!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/16-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 22:23:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/16-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>урок 20 p. 273
+++++
You drink a lot of carot juice.
Вы пьёте много морковного сока.
+++++
You sing a lot of songs.
Вы поёте много песен.
+++++
Difference between петь (to sing) and пить (to drink) is small: Я пью (I drink), я пою (I sing).
Твоя́ но́вая маши́на — про́сто пе́сня!
+++++
Your new car really rocks (it&amp;rsquo;s just a song)!
есть
+++++
я ем
ты ешь</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/15-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 11:39:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/15-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>That girl looks funny on the inside.
  Mildly disquieting how she looks like Trump when faking a quiff.
Pussy Riot in Diksmuide 😮.
Why is scanning strings with regular expressions and getting unexpected matches so entertaining?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/14-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 14:17:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/14-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>When you write that song boasting about ruling the neighbourhood but in the Youtube comments everyone is crazy about the chorus by some Celine Dionesque singer.
  +++++
  It&amp;rsquo;s catchy.
Someone has to rock the boat.
Respect voor de dwerg (no offence) in maatpak die ik eerder deze week tegenkwam. Symbool van conformisme omgezet in symbool van verzet. Je weet hoe iedereen je ziet, maar dat hoeft niet te zijn zoals je jezelf ziet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/13-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 22:25:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/13-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>свет осени особенный.
+++++
The light in autumn is special.
+++++
осо́ба +‎ -енный: особа means person, suffix енный makes it adjective. What is personal, is special.
время года.
+++++
Season.
+++++
Literally: the time of the year.
Зима, весна, лето или осень, всё, что вам нужно сделать, это позвонить.
+++++
Winter, spring, summer or fall, all you have to do is call.
+++++
  влоз: весна, лето, осень, Зима (all seasons have very short names, probably because they&amp;rsquo;re such basic words they&amp;rsquo;ve been around for a long time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/12-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 22:38:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/12-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Я встретил президента сегодня.
Я думаю он странный.
+++++
I met a president today. I think he&amp;rsquo;s weird.
+++++
сегодня: г is pronounced as в in this case since сегодня is derived from сего + дня (this day). его is always pronounced as в.
день always changes to дн + ending.
+++++
как я могу заснуть, если я не найду свои ключи!
+++++
How can I go to sleep if I don&amp;rsquo;t find my keys!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/11-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 19:57:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/11-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>только бог знает.
+++++
Only God knows.
Я её хорошо знаю
+++++
I know her well.
+++++
её = accusative of она (she)
Где ты его нашел?
+++++
Where did you find him?
+++++
его = accusative of он (he)
Однажды в Германии кто-то сказал нет. один, два, три, четыре, пять, шесть, семь, восемь, девять.
+++++
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine. Once in Germany someone said nein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/10-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 22:10:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/10-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Борис самый большой молодец всех времен.
+++++
Boris is the biggest little boy of all times.
+++++
самый большой = most big = biggest
молодец &amp;lt; молодой which means young. ец is a suffix appended to adjectives to create a masculine noun denoting a person having the adjective&amp;rsquo;s quality. So in this case a man who is young is a boy. The more conventional word for boy is мальчик which is interesting as well because it&amp;rsquo;s a combination of малый +‎ -чик.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create simplest web page possible</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/create-simplest-web-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 16:12:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/create-simplest-web-page/</guid>
      <description>Rationale Everyone comes in touch with the web every day. Opening a browser is as natural as waking up. Sadly enough, way less people know how the web really works. That&amp;rsquo;s a pity because once you know how it work possibilities are endless. You can start manipulating the web any way you want which is close to being a magician!
In this tutorial I&amp;rsquo;d like to show:
 web development isn&amp;rsquo;t hard to learn and learning it is fun while learning you are already creating something and creating is fun so you have already double fun and then you can share it sharing is also fun  So as you can see you&amp;rsquo;re set up for triple whammy of pleasure with this article.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>