<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog Isaac Verminck</title>
    <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog Isaac Verminck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 13:53:14 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a simple CLI with Click to learn Russian (part 1)</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/cli-russian/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 13:53:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/cli-russian/</guid>
      <description>Goal Unix philosophy In line with the Unix philosophy I wanted to build a small system which is as user-friendly as possible (even though I might be the only user). I chose a system which would help me with a personal goal namely learning Russian.
Learning Russian Recently I scraped example phrases for the most common Russian words. Based on Zipf&amp;rsquo;s law it makes sense to really focus on the most common words since the frequency of any word is inversely proportional to its rank in the frequency table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most common data manipulations implemented in awk and dplyr</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/most-common-data-manipulations-dplyr-awk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 14:51:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/most-common-data-manipulations-dplyr-awk/</guid>
      <description>Goal of this post We compare the most common data manipulations between dplyr and awk in terms of functionality.
As explained perfectly in the tidyverse article there are 5 types of common data manipulations:
 filter select mutate summarise arrange  I go over each of these manipulations and show using examples in dplyr and awk how to implement them.
Some aspects of these data manipulations are not covered in this article:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create simplest web page possible</title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/create-simplest-web-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 16:12:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/posts/create-simplest-web-page/</guid>
      <description>Rationale Everyone comes in touch with the web every day. Opening a browser is as natural as waking up. Sadly enough, way less people know how the web really works. That&amp;rsquo;s a pity because once you know how it work possibilities are endless. You can start manipulating the web any way you want which is close to being a magician!
In this tutorial I&amp;rsquo;d like to show:
 web development isn&amp;rsquo;t hard to learn and learning it is fun while learning you are already creating something and creating is fun so you have already double fun and then you can share it sharing is also fun  So as you can see you&amp;rsquo;re set up for triple whammy of pleasure with this article.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>