<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Observations on Blog Isaac Verminck</title>
    <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Observations on Blog Isaac Verminck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 19:38:05 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/26-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 19:38:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/26-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Some interesting eavesdropping.
The moment those drums kick in&amp;hellip;
Just under a century ago, the Soviet Union embarked on one of the strangest attempts to reshape the common calendar that has ever been undertaken. As Joseph Stalin raced to turn an agricultural backwater into an industrialized nation, his government downsized the week from seven to five days. Saturday and Sunday were abolished.
In place of the weekend, a new system of respite was introduced in 1929.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/25-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 12:18:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/25-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Almost poetry
  Failed company wanted to charge $15 for $10 in quarters.
Clean as a whistle.
  But neither the &amp;ldquo;Spurs&amp;rdquo; nor Ajax are Jewish clubs, and their number of Jewish fans is not particularly high. So why the Jewish symbolism?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/24-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 22:33:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/24-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>All of the sudden I felt like someone punched me in the stomach with a baseball bat. I got the wind knocked out of me and stumbled backwards. When I looked up there was a 40 oz. bottle at my feet. It had hit me in the gut/dick.
The perpetrator was a 300 lb. black sister who was standing right below me at my monitor. I looked her right in the eye and she waved me forward, as if she was going to tell me a secret.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/23-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 23:04:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/23-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Идти.
At any given moment, all sorts of objects are drifting in the ocean, a surprising number of them Americans. The Coast Guard plucks 10 people a day out of the ocean, on average.
Portrait of an Inessential Government Worker.
Need to do more research on this.
Postman to Paris.
We stopped talking about football. That was a problem, because football was our life.
On the pitch, strange things started to happen for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/22-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 21:27:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/22-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Sankey diagram
Pushing wood.
Mesmerizing Oskar Fischinger.
  How much longer can this nonsense go on?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/21-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 21:39:49 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/21-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>This decision was made to increase the amount of funding received from the European Union, which dedicates a third of its budget (50 billion euros) to less economically developed regions for investments in infrastructure, such as schools and hospitals. Yet when regions improve economically, they no longer qualify for the same amount of funding. As a type of statistical gerrymandering, governors of these regions—like in Hungary—have redrawn their borders in order to keep the money flowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/20-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 20:20:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/20-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Troposphere 5
  Andy Warhol New York Diet.
“When I order in a restaurant, I order everything that I don’t want, so I have a lot to play around with while everyone else eats,” he wrote in The Philosophy of Andy Warhol. “Then, no matter how chic the restaurant is, I insist that the waiter wrap the entire plate up like a to-go order, and after we leave the restaurant I find a little corner outside in the street to leave the plate in, because there are so many people in New York who live in the streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/18-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 16:18:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/18-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>#YouTubeRegrets is a crowdsourced public awareness campaign run by the nonprofit Mozilla. Mozilla collected YouTube users’ stories about the platform’s recommendation engine leading them down bizarre and sometimes dangerous pathways.
Photoshop before Photoshop.
Sommige dingen veranderen nooit.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/17-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 21:24:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/17-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Österreich and its hiding.
Dutch police are questioning an Austrian man after a family of six were found in a secret room at a remote farmhouse in the Netherlands where they are believed to have been living for nearly a decade.
  Criminal activity of government informants.
Ich???
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/16-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 22:28:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/16-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Nah.
Newly introduced young woman: “There are two things I don’t like about you…your new moustache and…your new political party.”
Churchill: “Pray do not disturb yourself, you are not likely to come into contact with either.”
Tal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/15-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 23:21:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/15-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>How the hell can a person
go to work in the morning
and come home in the evening
and have nothing to say.
  Goe poeier!
но время и случай для всех их.
Экклезиаст, глава 9, стих 11    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/14-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 23:02:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/14-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Penitentials were handbooks carried by some priests in the Middle Ages that delineated various sins for private confession and their penances. They were full of strict limitations as to what constituted pious behavior. They went on and on. To digest it all, James A Brundage, a scholar of the Crusades, aggregated the complex rules about sex into this excellent flowchart.
Play it fucking loud.
  My state of mind&amp;rsquo;s all purple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/13-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 12:10:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/13-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>People think that creativity comes from freedom. That&amp;rsquo;s a fundamental misunderstanding. Creativity comes from obstacles, limitations and questions.
Game of life, so easy and so complex.
Wonder if that woof sound has a name.
          Make each program do one thing well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/11-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 14:48:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/11-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Petrus Alexiowitz, tsaar van Moskou, groothertog, heeft zittend aan de rand van deze fontein de wateren verrijkt met de wijn die hij heeft gedronken om drie uur in de namiddag op 16 april 1717.
Доверяй, но проверяй (words are the wise man&amp;rsquo;s counters and the fool&amp;rsquo;s money)
вера = trust
До and про refer to completion, so almost no difference between to check and to trust.
Road trip.
There&amp;rsquo;s value in randomly picking up books.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/09-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 23:02:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/09-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Tatiana Samoilova in Летят журавли.
+++++
Audrey Hepburn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/08-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 22:23:38 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/08-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>The UK is the biggest tax haven.
For decades, places such as Anguilla, the British Virgin Islands, Gibraltar and others sold the companies that people hide behind when committing their crimes. But in recent years, the world has changed – those jurisdictions have been cajoled, bullied and persuaded to keep good records of company ownership, and to reveal those records when police officers come looking. They are no longer as useful as they used to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/07-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 23:22:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/07-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Turing tarpit.
Beware of the Turing tar-pit in which everything is possible but nothing of interest is easy.
Einst kam ich auf eine mögliche Vorstellung die Hölle betreffend. Die Hölle ist eine Ansammlung einzelner Personen, die den Großteil ihrer Zeit damit verbringen, eine Arbeit zu erledigen, die sie nicht mögen und die sie nicht besonders gut beherrschen.
It wasn’t until the next morning that I realized I was a thief.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/06-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 21:35:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/06-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>You are just a goy!
  Ben, j’ai été éduqué par des femmes, hein. C’est pour ça que je suis lesbienne.
Not a bad game at all and at least I played without any major blunders. Hasn&amp;rsquo;t happened for a long time.
 You want to separate the creative process of seeing that the geometry is there for a fork from the editing process of analyzing whether the fork can be made profitable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/05-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 13:16:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/05-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Everything we do is interpreted and translated time and again as it works its way down through all of the metaphors and abstractions (In the beginning was the Command Line).
In an art project that has been compared to The Truman Show, Big Brother and the Charlie Kaufman film Synecdoche, New York, a Russian artist has paid 400 people to live for three years in a fictional but functioning Stalin-era research institute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/04-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 17:15:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/04-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>WW2 material still in use today&amp;hellip;
  Nixon.
THE POSITION The position is To withhold Information And to cover up This is Totally true. You could say This is Totally untrue.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/03-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 21:42:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/03-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Everyone needs their asylum:
It is an asylum or &amp;ndash; what do they call them now? &amp;ndash; a rest home, for the infirm, the aged, the discontent, and the otherwise incompetent. Look at the three of us &amp;ndash; we are the University. The stranger would not know that we have so much in common, but we know, don&amp;rsquo;t we. We know well.
Telling tales of drunkenness and cruelty.
  золотая осень</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/02-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 21:56:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/02-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Midas.
Robots fighting. So many styles.
    Cleaning up those Youtube pearls one by one.
  Koala.
Because of its small brain, the koala has a limited ability to perform complex, unfamiliar behaviours. For example, when presented with plucked leaves on a flat surface, the animal cannot adapt to the change in its normal feeding routine and will not eat the leaves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/01-10-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 22:01:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/01-10-2019/</guid>
      <description>Cut up your hair, straighten your curls. Well, your problems hide in your curls.
Hopper.
Didn&amp;rsquo;t plan to go back to Super Hexagon ever again but CANNOT RESIST.
Thursday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/30-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 23:00:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/30-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Carrier bag theory.
Not only is the carrier bag theory plausible, it also does meaningful ideological work — shifting the way we look at humanity&amp;rsquo;s foundations from a narrative of domination to one of gathering, holding, and sharing. Because I am, despite my best efforts, often soppy and sentimental, I sometimes imagine this like a really comforting group hug. But it’s not, really: the carrier bag holds things, sure, but it’s also messy and sometimes conflicted</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/29-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 23:32:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/29-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Sorry little hedgehog!
Demesne is pronounced as dimain. Mindblowing.
Structured procrastination:
Anyone can do any amount of work, provided it isn&amp;rsquo;t the work he is supposed to be doing at that moment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/28-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 15:11:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/28-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Another chess analysis but this time I annotated a bit different than I did for the one of 24-09-2019:
 less focus on strategy only using local analysis tags  Blunders made are still quite big. These have to be purged first before making sound strategic decisions pay off.
By default Lichess annotates your game with automated comments like blunder, mistake,&amp;hellip; I found those quite annoying but since there&amp;rsquo;s no option to turn them off somehow forcing you to manually remove them one by one, for the time being I choose to only use local analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/26-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 21:50:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/26-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Yeah.
Being in New York compounded a feeling I had been experiencing, of profound dissociation from my own life. I knew, as I wandered through museums with friends and video-chatted with Ian, that I needed to leave the tech industry. I was no longer high on the energy of being around people who so easily satisfied their desires––on the feeling that everything was just within reach. The industry’s hubris and naïveté were beginning to grate; I had moral, political, and personal misgivings about Silicon Valley’s accelerating colonization of art, work, everyday life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/25-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 21:33:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/25-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Nice intro to my programming course book. Fuck all that serious shit!
Christian the absolute mad lad.
From the book by C.V. Wedgwood I&amp;rsquo;m reading on the Thirty Years&amp;rsquo; War.
How to make sure you get your money if you pass a village:
He had issued startling letters, suggestively burnt at the four corners, and bearing the words &amp;lsquo;Fire! Fire! Blood! Blood!&amp;rsquo; to every sizeable village he passed.
Or how to handle a right arm amputation graciously:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/24-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 22:49:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/24-09-2019/</guid>
      <description> Quite a bad game on my part with some horrendous blunders at the end as the cherry on the cake. But at least I made a post game analysis for once.
Some general things to remember are:
 dare choose the more aggressive move if possible (why not go for that sweet queen exchange???) do not play when it gets too late (but I know that rule will always be broken)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/23-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 22:15:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/23-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Hehe.
Article about a creepy subject that isn&amp;rsquo;t so creepy.
With lots of informative pictures:
Could be.
A disappearance begins internally, experienced en masse, but with each one—roses, photographs, and fruit follow—long-coated, stone-faced Memory Police sweep through the village, ensuring that all traces of the disappeared concept or object is gone for good. What exactly causes disappearances is never addressed; instead, the mystery lies in how far they&amp;rsquo;ll go, and what role the Memory Police play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/22-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 19:14:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/22-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Rehearsing Russian course 1 of 16/09/2019 (p.273-277).
глагол: verb
sing/song: петь/песня
eat/food: есть/еда
drink/drink: пить/напиток
wash/soap: мыть/мыло
+++++
петь (по)
пить (пь)
мыть (мо)
+++++
я ем
ты ешь
он ест
мы едим
вы едите
они едят
+++++
he ate: он ел
we washed: они мыли
weak/strong: слабый/громкий
hot/cold: горячий/холодный
low/high: низкий/высокий
usually: обычно
table wine: столовое вино
singer: певец/певица
drunk: пьяный
often: часто
foreigner: иностранец (иной + страна = other + country)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/19-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 22:32:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/19-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Nothing much today but maybe this mystery finally gets resolved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/18-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 21:49:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/18-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>The 11-23 most common verbs in Russian.
Some verbs are skipped because they form perfective/imperfective pairs. For example there&amp;rsquo;s делать/сделать but at the moment I only focus on remembering the easiest form (whether perfective or imperfective).
Main version:
   Russian English remark verb     На этой станции поезд стоит 10 минут. The train stops for ten minutes in this station. стан - ции стоять   Я думаю о тебе.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/17-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 21:45:59 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/17-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>The 10 most common verbs in Russian with some handy phrase to remember them by.
Added multiple phrases for some verbs (e.g. стать) who have multiple, widely divergent meanings.
   Russian English remark verb     Так было, так есть и так будет всегда. So it was, so it is, and so it will always be! National anthem of Russia быть   Легко сказать! Easy to say!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/16-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 22:23:55 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/16-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>урок 20 p. 273
+++++
You drink a lot of carot juice.
Вы пьёте много морковного сока.
+++++
You sing a lot of songs.
Вы поёте много песен.
+++++
Difference between петь (to sing) and пить (to drink) is small: Я пью (I drink), я пою (I sing).
Твоя́ но́вая маши́на — про́сто пе́сня!
+++++
Your new car really rocks (it&amp;rsquo;s just a song)!
есть
+++++
я ем
ты ешь</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/15-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 11:39:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/15-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>That girl looks funny on the inside.
  Mildly disquieting how she looks like Trump when faking a quiff.
Pussy Riot in Diksmuide 😮.
Why is scanning strings with regular expressions and getting unexpected matches so entertaining?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/14-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 14:17:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/14-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>When you write that song boasting about ruling the neighbourhood but in the Youtube comments everyone is crazy about the chorus by some Celine Dionesque singer.
  +++++
  It&amp;rsquo;s catchy.
Someone has to rock the boat.
Respect voor de dwerg (no offence) in maatpak die ik eerder deze week tegenkwam. Symbool van conformisme omgezet in symbool van verzet. Je weet hoe iedereen je ziet, maar dat hoeft niet te zijn zoals je jezelf ziet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/13-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 22:25:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/13-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>свет осени особенный.
+++++
The light in autumn is special.
+++++
осо́ба +‎ -енный: особа means person, suffix енный makes it adjective. What is personal, is special.
время года.
+++++
Season.
+++++
Literally: the time of the year.
Зима, весна, лето или осень, всё, что вам нужно сделать, это позвонить.
+++++
Winter, spring, summer or fall, all you have to do is call.
+++++
  влоз: весна, лето, осень, Зима (all seasons have very short names, probably because they&amp;rsquo;re such basic words they&amp;rsquo;ve been around for a long time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/12-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 22:38:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/12-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Я встретил президента сегодня.
Я думаю он странный.
+++++
I met a president today. I think he&amp;rsquo;s weird.
+++++
сегодня: г is pronounced as в in this case since сегодня is derived from сего + дня (this day). его is always pronounced as в.
день always changes to дн + ending.
+++++
как я могу заснуть, если я не найду свои ключи!
+++++
How can I go to sleep if I don&amp;rsquo;t find my keys!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/11-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 19:57:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/11-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>только бог знает.
+++++
Only God knows.
Я её хорошо знаю
+++++
I know her well.
+++++
её = accusative of она (she)
Где ты его нашел?
+++++
Where did you find him?
+++++
его = accusative of он (he)
Однажды в Германии кто-то сказал нет. один, два, три, четыре, пять, шесть, семь, восемь, девять.
+++++
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine. Once in Germany someone said nein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/10-09-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 22:10:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://isaacverm.github.io/observations/10-09-2019/</guid>
      <description>Борис самый большой молодец всех времен.
+++++
Boris is the biggest little boy of all times.
+++++
самый большой = most big = biggest
молодец &amp;lt; молодой which means young. ец is a suffix appended to adjectives to create a masculine noun denoting a person having the adjective&amp;rsquo;s quality. So in this case a man who is young is a boy. The more conventional word for boy is мальчик which is interesting as well because it&amp;rsquo;s a combination of малый +‎ -чик.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>